<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<men>
	<name>Men</name>
	<description>Bible studies designed for the men audience.</description>
	<lessons>
		<name>By Grace, Through Faith</name>
		<author>Bible Study Planet</author>
		<email>contact@biblestudyplanet.com</email>
		<date>02/29/2012</date>
		<topic>Family</topic>
		<focus>Old Testament</focus>
		<book>Exodus</book>
		<audience>Men</audience>
		<length>90</length>
		<lesson>&quot;It is by grace you have been saved, through faith — and this not from yourselves, it is the gift of God — not by works, so that no one can boast.&quot; – Ephesians 2:8-9 God is gracious… Because God is gracious, sinful people are forgiven, converted, purified, and saved. It’s not because of anything in them, or anything that ever can be in them, that they are saved; it’s because of the boundless love, goodness, pity, compassion, mercy, and grace of God. It’s because “his love endures forever” (1 Chronicles 16:41) that we are not destroyed. It’s because “his compassions never fail” (Lamentations 3:22) that sinners are brought to Him and forgiven. Remember these things or you may fall into error by focusing so much on your faith that you forget that grace is the source of faith itself.</lesson>
	</lessons>
	<lessons>
		<name>Honoring Our Parents Part 3; How We Honor Our Parents</name>
		<author>Pastor Terry Gurno</author>
		<email>contact@biblestudyplanet.com</email>
		<date>02/03/2012</date>
		<topic>Family</topic>
		<focus>Old Testament</focus>
		<book>Exodus</book>
		<audience>Men</audience>
		<length>90</length>
		<lesson>Why Should We Obey Our Parents? Because God promises you a long life. Notice at the end of this Commandment it says, “Honor your father and mother so that you may live long in the land the Lord your God is giving you.” (Exodus 20:12). So not only live long, but notice it says, “In the land your God is giving you.” He is not talking about individuals, He is talking about society and when the family unit breaks down, the society breaks down. Nobody knows that better than the United States of America because it is the greatest battle, and it is the greatest challenge that we face. The preservation of the family unit is the preservation of generations to follow. The family is the backbone of society. “That you may live long in the land as a society, as a unit,” that’s what God is really talking about.</lesson>
	</lessons>
	<lessons>
		<name>3 Things You Need To Know Before (And After) You Become A Christian </name>
		<author>Bible Study Planet</author>
		<email>contact@biblestudyplanet.com</email>
		<date>02/10/2012</date>
		<topic>Christian Life</topic>
		<focus>New Testament</focus>
		<book>Romans</book>
		<audience>Men</audience>
		<length>90</length>
		<lesson>There are three things a person needs to know in order to become a Christian and then live a fulfilling life in Christ.1) You need to know you are a sinner. 2) You need to know how you can be forgiven for your sins. 3) You need to know how you should respond to God’s forgiveness. Why this is important to know: In order to grow in Christ we need to know how to respond to God’s grace. What Christ has done for us effects how we live. We do good works, not to be saved, but because Christ has saved us (Eph 2:10). We forgive because Christ has forgiven us (Matt 6:12). We bless because Christ has blessed us (Eph 1:3). We served because Christ has served us (Mrk 10:45). We love because Christ has loved us (1 Jhn 4:19).</lesson>
	</lessons>
</men>